A true zoo story.
We Bought a Zoo is a drama, comedy, family film directed by Cameron Crowe.
Benjamin has lost his wife and, in a bid to start his life over, purchases a large house that
has a zoo – welcome news for his daughter, but his son is not happy about it.
The zoo is in need of renovation and Benjamin sets about the work with the head keeper
and the rest of the staff, but, the zoo soon runs into financial trouble.
Benjamin Mee, played by Matt Damon.
Kelly Foster, played by Scarlett Johansson.
Duncan Mee, played by Thomas Haden Church.
Dylan Mee, played by Colin Ford.
Rosie Mee, played by Maggie Elizabeth Jones.
Peter MacCready, played by Angus Macfadyen.
We Bought a Zoo is a 2011 American biographical comedy drama film loosely
based on the 2008 memoir of the same name by Benjamin Mee.
It was co-written and directed by Cameron Crowe and stars Matt Damon as widowed father Benjamin Mee, who purchases a
dilapidated zoo with his family and takes on the challenge of preparing the zoo for its reopening to the public.
The film also stars Scarlett Johansson, Maggie Elizabeth Jones, Thomas Haden Church,
Patrick Fugit, Elle Fanning, Colin Ford, and John Michael Higgins.
The film is based on the Dartmoor Zoological Park, which is a 33-acre zoological
garden located near the village of Sparkwell, Devon, England.
We Bought a Zoo was released in the United States on
December 21, 2011, by 20th Century Fox.
A critical and commercial success, the film grossed $120 million on a
$50 million budget, and received various accolades.
The film explores themes of countryside, rain, zoo, based on true story, love.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.